esr.cri.nz 2018-01-27

# Privacy policy | ESR

Information transmitted over the Internet is inherently insecure, unless pages use encryption to protect the information during transmission.

ESR websites have security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control.

In order to maintain the cyber security of ESR systems and information, ESR systems are subject to ongoing monitoring (including activity logging) analysis and auditing.

#### Anonymous access

ESR is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. You can access and browse our website without disclosing your personal information. Any information automatically retrieved during your visit, such as IP address, browser type and pages visited, is anonymous and is used for statistical analysis of the use of this site, and to prevent unauthorised access or attacks or to resolve such events. We may use this information even if you are not involved in such activity.

ESR may use the services from one or more third party suppliers to monitor or maintain the cyber security of its systems and information. These third party suppliers will have access to monitoring and logging information, as well as information processed on ESR websites and other IT systems.

Use of ESR websites and/or other IT systems implies acceptance of their information being monitored.

#### What personal information do we collect?

We only collect information that you actively give us by inputting your personal details on to a web form on our site, emailing your personal details to ESR or giving your personal details to a member of our staff. This usually includes your name, job title, organisation, mailing address, email address and phone number.

You may update personal information held by ESR at any time by contacting us at [enquiries@esr.cri.nz](mailto:enquiries@esr.cri.nz "enquiries@esr.cri.nz").

#### What will we use your information for?

Once ESR receives any personal information from you, your data will be added to an ESR database. ESR will hold that information securely and will only use such information for the purpose that you gave it to us:

  * to provide you with publications that you have requested
  * to notify you when new material that you have expressed interest in is available
  * to respond to a service or information request

#### How long will we keep your personal information for?

Periodically we will check that you still want us to retain your information and that it is up-to-date. You can at any time request that your information be removed from our database.
